# JUANMA CANALS

jmcanals98@gmail.com | 652647863

My name is Juanma and I'm a Telecom Engineer with +3 years of experience in different engineering fields, such as Software Development and Solution Design, Project Management, R&D, IT Operations... but mainly I have learned how service is given to customers. I am very passionate about the SRE profession and would love to be an example of SRE in the future. I am seeking change; I want to find a place where I can help in the delivery of state-of-the-art technologies and software solutions.

# **Professional Experience**

IBM/Kyndryl
SRE @ Banc Sabadell
Barcelona, Spain
July 2019 – Now

Working for Banc Sabadell client in IT Operations department focused on Monitoring, Automation and Operations improvement applying SRE Google Tenets.

- Incident automatic remediation achieving a 30% reduction of manual action integrating Event Management Tool, Ticketing Tool, and Automation Tool (Netcool, ServiceNow, Ansible Tower).
- Alerting noise reduction analyzing data of our events, detecting some problems in our monitoring tools. The result of this analysis ended up in a reduction of 85% of the events generated.
- Panic buttons automation: some of the IT Operations processes that must be executed when Major Incidents occur are very manual. Integrating multiple tools, like Ansible Tower, TWS (Mainframe), Azure, AWS... I reduced the time of activating incident mitigation by 90%.
- Always involved in client-faced roles, managing projects and teams (+10 people) and assuring delivery times. Multiple projects were deployed in Hybrid-cloud infrastructure (Openshift over AWS...)

Development/Monitoring Department

- Docker, Jenkins, and CI/CD environment implementation.
- · Angular and Back-end (PHP) development.
- Shellscripting and Linux system administration for automation purposes mainly.
- · Grafana, Alertmanager and Exporters stack management

#### **Iberia SRE Profession Lead**

December 2020 - Now

I am leading the Spain & Portugal SRE Community for Kyndryl, helping with the role expansion, Client Units SRE culture adoption, community engagement, and coordination...

#### **Strategic Startups Alliances Coordinator**

January 2021 - Now

I am responsible for analyzing and reaching out to startups aligned with our culture and practices, to explore and close strategic alliances.

Kamleon

R&D Intern

Barcelona, Spain

Jan 2020 – July 2020

Development of health monitoring systems based on Machine Learning algorithms.

- Acquisition of biometrical data through sensors like ECG, PPG, and SpO2, integrated into a bathroom toilet.
- Data processing using Python libraries, formatting data to be analyzed.
- Recognize between 6 different people only using ECG data acquired, by **ML algorithms in Python**.

#### Quside Firmware Developer Intern

Barcelona, Spain

July 2019 – Sept 2019

• I worked with 7 series FPGAs like Kintex and Artix, and developed firmware to manage communication protocols (like AXI4) and writing/readings from memory (like DRAMs)

## **Education**

#### Universitat Rovira I Virgili

Sept 2016 – July 2020

#### **Telecomunications Engineering Degree: 8.6/10 (Best of promotion)**

· Courses: OOP in C, Java, Algorithms, Data Structures, Android App Development

## **Skills**

**Programming Languages**: C, Python, Java, Angular JS, Shellscripting, VHDL, Matlab, PHP **Technologies**: Bash, Git, Docker, Linux Administration, APIs, Monitoring Tools, Jenkins

**Certifications**: IBM Agile Explorer, Leadership Practical Skills, Oral Presentation Courses, Kyndryl SRE Bootcamp, Google Devops Engineer (started)

Languages:

Catalan and Spanish: Native.

English: Professional Working Efficiency.